hello it's February 22nd 2023
and we're in the second discussion
of chapter seven
in cohort two
before we go to the questions of chapter
seven and then at the end to look ahead
to chapter eight
we are going to have Thomas Parr joined
for a live stream in five days
and so anybody if they would like to
raise
an area of questions could be conceptual
or it could just be a general
textbook level or personal question so
of course feel free to add anything but
just while we're here any thought or
like kind of General
piece that people are thinking that
Thomas could reduce our uncertainty
about
all right just of course
add it when you see fit
okay
um there were several
questions that we've already looked at
from seven
and several more
we can also look a little bit more
just again we we looked at the first
sections of
the chapter itself
so
does anyone have a chapter 7 question
that they want to go to or ADD
or
do they prefer to walk through
the sections in the textbook
let's look at equation 7.4
see if we have anything
annotated for it
okay we don't have the natural language
yet
so let's just look a little let's pick
back up
with the um rat in the Maze example
go through it connect it to the
equations and then return to some to
several of the um
uh questions down here
in seven
um
so in the earliest part of chapter seven
was a passive inference with the example
of listening to music
now
the upstairs action selection part is
going to come into play
the imperative for Action selection is
going to be G
like we saw in chapter 5
takes the action prior
the prior on different policies
which can be understood as like habit
and then
sharpens it
according to just qualitatively
provide epistemic and pragmatic value
and quantitatively
as described in equation 2.6 and 7.4
does anyone want to give a reading or a
thought on 7.4
just what is it saying
in and of itself
and or
how does or might this relate to in
their words the resolution of the
exploration exploitation dilemma
yeah I'll go for it
foreign
we saw before in chapter two I guess
um but I think it was in a more
comprehensive terms but here we only
have a part of that equation which
basically deals with the trade-off
between a negative
um I mean epistemic value and the
pragmatic value
and how they relate to each other
because
um as we saw in Chapter 2
the trade-off or the Dilemma between
exploration and exploitation
um is basically
uh one of the fundamental requirements
for any
sentient behavior for any sentient agent
because as long as
the agent
tries to uh
ex wants to explore the environment in
order to
um
informally discover a new
um new let's say opportunities or new uh
resources be it uh I don't know food
resource or any other resource necessary
for its survival in the environment it
needs to somehow have a trade-off
between this kind of having
the pragmatic value on one hand namely
to survive in the environment and on the
other hand
to ex to discover new resources for its
survival
which basically relates to
the pragmatic value but
either of those two requirements
um if taken to uh to its extreme far uh
would probably result in the demise of
the agent because
um so take for instance an agent uh
residing in an environment but
for a specific a certain
period of time it can't survive in that
environment using the pre-known
resources there but uh when the
resources is about to
um
is about
um to diminish then that agent need to
explore a little bit a little bit
further in order to discover some new uh
resources and
continue it's persistent Through Time
word survival
yeah great
yes Michael
oh yeah yeah so so I'm I'm a little bit
wondering the the in this epistemic
um considerations
uh only
things can be considered that the
agent actually already knows about right
um
and and then I'm
wondering why at several places I think
it said this in chapter two and here in
this chapter also seven two also that um
that one would like to find the most
unlikely path
or one would like to uh to to increase
the information value means when yeah
um that's what I understood so the past
that should be searched for would be the
path that maximizes uh information which
is uh means it's the the most uncertain
path
um and
um
correct
there's there's aspects that I think are
are correct but I just want to draw that
out so actually what is being selected
for policy
are the most likely paths what is an
agent like me most likely to do we're
sampling our actions from the action
posterior
so rather than scaling policies by their
reward and ranking them by the reward
in reward learning and choosing sampling
from the reward posterior for example
we're going to be sampling from an
action posterior so
um in the sense that our actions are
selected based upon their posterior
likelihood we're actually pursuing the
most likely path of action indeed the
path of least action however we are
seeking in the epistemic component
especially
maximally informative
sequences of future observations
so in the special case where pragmatic
value doesn't matter
like we have no preference over outcomes
we don't we don't we don't care if our
bank account goes up or down
then we Implement a pure info Max
novelty search
in a situation that's totally
um known there's no epistemic value to
be obtained
we have a special case of pure utility
pragmatic value
however in cases where both utility
pragmatic and epistemic are on the table
G
is proposed to resolve this dilemma
by adjusting the action prior into an
action posterior that respects
the importance of both of those
imperatives
that's the unified imperative of
action and inference
yeah so so so
I'm I'm not sure how I should understand
this so for instance I want to go to the
bakery and buy some bread
and then the most informative I mean the
more unlikely thing is actually that I
go to the barber and cut my hairs so I
would con I would because that has more
information and going to the Baker and
considering what kind of bread I'm going
to buy I I I I I I go to the barber
because that is more that is more
informative I'm not sure I understand
how I should understand this
these values are calculated about
generative models not about territories
so we again it's it's natural intuitive
to want to be like
directly mapping from an equation or
calculation to a real world territory
situation
but keep in mind these are
um ultimately numerical values
calculated for generative model it
doesn't make sense to talk about free
energy being minimized like for example
if a person doing translation simply or
of an ant simply foraging it's of the
generative model that these values are
being calculated on
and so if one proposes a generative
model of location
Behavior so kind of in a previous
discussion we had like a higher order
like what location am I going to Barber
home Baker you know and then we have a
lower level model with our footsteps so
that's kind of analogous to the live
stream 42 slam robotics example
then in that situation
one could ask how different policy
selections
were being influenced
by their respective epistemic or
pragmatic value but it is not the case
that we can directly draw from a
variable
to the territory
these are like summary variables or
re-weightings on our map and it only
makes sense to talk about these
summaries on maps not territories Ali
actually Michael Levin has an excellent
paper from 2019 the computational
boundary of a self
in which he has an interesting diagram
showing the
cognitive sphere or cognitive light
comes if you will of each cognitive or
intelligent agent in which it can have
an effect and it's
of a more or less a
it's concerned so uh it also integrates
the yeah that's it
so uh so for example
um for humans uh because of uh well or
highly intelligent uh species or agents
uh because of the complexity of its
goal-directed activity and agency it
results in a kind of larger cognitive
boundaries and for uh somewhat uh let's
say quote-unquote simpler agents that
would result in a much smaller light
cone area of cognitive boundaries uh so
yeah
depending on the complexity of the tasks
that the agent is capable of doing that
territory of
its cognitive effectivity would vary
according to the complexity of the
thesis
yeah
so
these are
G is a functional
that is going to sharpen our action
prior
according to such and such
if we just wanted to pass through habit
we would just pass through habit and
um in chapter 5
in the nervous system example
this is what's reflected in the bottom
here with this dopaminergic circuitry
where on the left side of this basal
ganglia or whatever mammalian tissue it
happens to be
on the left side there's kind of like a
habit pass through like e the prior on
affordance is basically passed through
whereas in G I'm sorry on the right side
G
is sharpening
the policy distribution so if we just
want to pass through have it we don't
even need to apply G
however if we want to sharpen
our action selection the moment to
respect expected free energy in a
prospective planning like fashion then
we want to calculate
um G so what is being calculated with G
again this is an equation 2.6 but also
here we're taking another look at it so
there's two terms
looking first at the pragmatic value
and the special cases were already
mentioned and elsewhere about when one
of these or the other is zero okay so
fancy e it's an expectation
regarding RQ variational distribution
that we control
of
otilda observation sequence conditioned
upon policy
so we're going to see that both terms
are conditioned upon policy
so if there's only two affordances
then we're only going to compute two
different G's so this is how we kind of
prevent like spiraling and Computing
like all possible World futures
we're conditioning on action
and we're interested in we're reducing
our uncertainty about which actions to
take
so that's what this first part is saying
so expectation of the variational
distribution
of upcoming observation sequences
conditioned upon actions policies that
we can take
and
it is going to be
um
a natural log to help facilitate just
all kinds of things that logs facilitate
but it's it's a monotonic relationship
with
what is being described here
and this is about
observations conditioned on preferences
C
so where observations
are close to preferences
pragmatic value is high
where are observations are different
than our preferences pragmatic value is
low
rather than associating pragmatic value
with a reward function
we're associating it with bounding our
surprise
natural log
self-information surprisal
of our preference slash expectation
the epistemic value component
which can be kind of seen as like a sub
function with like a negative I
um
but it's interesting that also that this
is kind of a surprisal like
um like even pragmatic value
enters into an information theoretic
surprise like formulation
so even our pragmatic value is still
informational
it's not
you know
tokens
here we see again an expectation over
our variational distribution but here
rather than on the sequence of
observations through time otilda it's
the sequence of hidden States Through
Time
so this is
um now looking at
underlying latent States conditioned
upon policy
and there's two there's a difference of
two entropies
then here's P which is like the the kind
of actual distribution and then Q the
distribution we control
now within the parentheses o tilde in
both case
o tilde conditioned upon States
minus o tilde conditioned upon policies
so there's definitely a few ways to
unpack it and I think we've we've um
explored sum
but um
broadly
if the policy
is not further reducing your uncertainty
about this relationship
the epistemic value is low
if the policy
is reducing your uncertainty
about s
via o
then there's epistemic value
I think there's like a lot of open
questions that are pretty contextual
like how do these implicit or tacit
understandings like how does the rat
know that going to that Q location is
going to reduce its uncertainty
how does it know the semantics of the
left versus the right cue
how does it know what you know
this is not the whole story
but within the context of doing
variational inference on a structurally
determined model
this is the basis of the separation
between pragmatic value defined as
alignment between observations and
preferences
and epistemic value defined as reduction
of uncertainty which is to say entropy
of how policies sharpen our
understanding of the relationship
between hidden States and observations
Michael
yeah so so both of these are
expectations so that
um
that is with respect to Future
things that might happen
both these expectations are actually in
the used in a sense of a mean the time
Horizon is implicit within pi
whether that is being calculated whether
G is being calculated over Pi of length
one two three Etc in the discrete time
formalization but these expectations are
actually like center of gravity LaPlace
approximation Central limit theorem
think expectation of a distribution even
though it's like about the future
we're actually Computing like the center
of gravity
or policies of different times but we're
not funny enough like like we are but we
aren't talking about future time
okay so what I maybe don't really
understand here is the difference
between p and Q I I was of the
understanding that P is something that
we
uh that is present in the in the
presence that we experience and Pew is
something that happens in the future
now I'm a little bit confused because p
and Q both relate here in this equation
to the Future right so how can this be
understood
um the difference between p and Q is not
between the present and the future
p is like the underlying
distribution and Q is our variational
approximation
so this is like the actual entropy of
the relationship
between observations and hidden States
whereas this is the relationship of the
entropy
um the entropy of the variational
generative models relationship between
those two Ali
uh yeah I think uh equation
2.3 might tell to somehow clarify that
ambiguity between p and Q because in
equation 2.3
um yeah that's it
the KL Divergence between
q and P is defined as the expectation
between the surprisal of Q and so the
surprise Loop p and one interesting
thing about equation 7.4 is that the
epistemic value is the expectation with
respect to the hidden States but the
pragmatic value is the expectation with
respect to the observations
so we need to keep both of them in mind
because here as Daniel just mentioned p
is just the
uh Q is the variational
um I mean the free energy but p is the
standard posterior the the standard
probability function we apply to a
random variable uh so that's why uh they
have distinguished between those two
um those two functions uh because a q
has uh some
um a specific
definition so for example in equation
2.2 uh the probability of P without any
uh yeah that's it that's just the simple
derivation of the probability of uh a
random variable being
of a specific value is calculated
without uh taken into account cues or
other parameters servers
nice yes the fact that pragmatic value
is associated with outcomes
is what ties closely to perceptual
control theory
and the fact that epistemic value is
associated with hidden States is related
to
the
um
avoidal of overfitting
we're not reducing our epistemic value
on observations
observations are being evaluated for
their pragmatic value hidden State
inferences are being evaluated and and
through them policies are being
evaluated for their epistemic value
Michael
yeah so
I'm a little bit confused about about
this you said that cure relates to the
variational free energy
but the variation of free energy I mean
we made this distinction between the G
which is the expected free energy and
the F which is the variation of free
energy and now inside that expected free
energy is a variational free energy and
so yeah just to be clear cues the
variational distribution this is the guy
we control
accuse the guy we control
P we don't mind your p's and q's Q is
the one we control
variational free energy
is a real-time functional
that's a function of
our variational density q and incoming
data it doesn't engage with planning
expected free energy
and
a host of cousins like free energy of
the expected future that Baron millage
and others have proposed so this is not
like the only way to even do this
energy-based method in the future
um
this is rather than a function of
um taking in only q and Y as arguments
here the primary argument is the policy
prior vector
and then the computation of this
functional involves
Q the variational distribution
but like Q could be a gaussian
distribution
so we'd be looking to parameterize the
variational parameters you know the
median and the variance
the two parameters of a gaussian
and the true
generative process may not be gaussian
but we would be looking just like in a
linear regression we'd be looking to
minimize the sum of squares with the L2
Norm
in this variational inference setting
we'd be looking to fit the best gaussian
mean and variance
given the the family of the variational
distributions that we had chosen
foreign
yeah so one other angle can be e is
actually the actual posterior
probability uh that uh is calculated uh
according to the actual States
um we have at our disposal but Q is the
approximate posterior so it's not the
exact posterior
that has been calculated in P but yeah Q
is related to variation of free energy
in the sense that it's deployed in
calculating the variation of free energy
because
for the in order for the free energy to
be uh attractable parameter uh to be
I mean implementable in a computational
task we need to use this approximate
variation of free energy because
otherwise we don't have uh either all
the information we need to calculate the
exact posteriors or it's too intractable
to compute so that's the reason behind
using approximate variational free
energy
great and I think one kind of as a
valiant this idea of like probably
approximately correct
which is kind of like when they say
almost surely
in math but more on the statistics side
if it's probably approximately correct
it's like actually within the context of
approximate Bays
that is what
is going to be
not just good enough but like as good as
you can kind of aim for
um
okay
matrices are defined
a has two slices
A1 and A2 are we going to give it as two
modalities of a
and the dimensionality
is
clear in the Matlab implementations it's
clear in the pi mdp it's not exactly
exactly the same syntax but like the
structure
of these matrices in principle are the
same
foreign
is describing
um
the probabilistic mapping from location
to exteroceptive cues
so it's not exactly an identity Matrix
but basically this is the accurate GPS
sensor when it's at this location start
location it knows exactly where it is
so again you can be like well how does
it get this implicit knowledge of where
it is
right that's part of the complexity of
cognitive modeling but suffice to say
that we're in a setting where the
location is known without error
but one can imagine that there would be
different outcomes and the need to do
different parameterizations if like
there were off diagonal elements
A2
is the um
probability
so they sum across to one
um or I'm sorry they they call them sum
to one
um
about
the the food location
the the between the spatial location and
then the outcome of food
so semantically this represents beliefs
about food location
in the a
here
7.5 is the same as 7.4 it's just that
here it's like two in the upper left 98
on the off
here we see 98 on the upper left two on
the off
here we have one in the third row empty
on the second here those two rows have
been flipped to represent the block on
the left side
versus the block on the right side
so
the food can be either on the left or
the right side
the rat can either make the move
to go to the left or the right side or
can go to the Q
if it decides to go for the Q
um not the Q letter but the c-u-e
if it decides to receive an
informational cue
then
um
it will find out where the food is again
check out model stream 7.2 with the
epistemic foraging and all of that sort
of um stuff okay
these
slices of B
are describing movement affordances
because again with respect to the hidden
State being location B describes how
different policy selection
Bears upon hidden States changing
Through Time
C is describing the relative preference
for different outcomes
so
um
the C1 vector
is about the first modality
five of them that's the locations and
there's a negative for the starting
location
so that's like a little bit of like a
like a kind of get going
because if it preferred to start
location it might just stay there
then in the second modality
that's referring to this shorter Vector
of these one two three and that's these
one two three
um
in various modeling settings we've
already started to see that like the C
scaling matters a lot
and so that's one reason why I think
it's tentative or hypothetical to say
that simply like equation 7.4 resolves
explore exploit
because it sets up the space for explore
exploit to be framed absolutely it does
however
depending on how the variables are
parameterized
you can end up with an agent who still
goes for the pragmatic value every time
or who still goes for the information
value every time
so in terms of outcomes it's not simply
resolved by knowing what equation 2.5 is
but rather this opens up a space of
modeling
in which adaptive Solutions can be
reached so if this was six thousand
then
zero six thousand zero it's like reward
is so good
it's going to be pursued if this was
flat zero zero zero then it would be
pure epistemic information
so that's why it's so important that we
develop statistical power methods
and parameter sweeps across simulations
because just making one teammates
and saying like Oh look The Rat does
this or that it's kind of like
okay
d
also is described for the two modalities
and um
it um
describes the priors on the two
there's a belief about the first
location
I'm actually just just I'm a little bit
curious why there's five elements here
but only four elements here
and then in the second modality there
which again is referring maybe this is
like a a minus there's one fewer
um element here because there's only two
here
um here's like reflecting an equal prior
over where the food is
so a priori is 50 50 left or right
so do you go do a 50 50 bet left or
right on the food
or do you go to get the epistemic cue
which of course reduces your uncertainty
about where the food is
now we're going to dive a little bit
deeper into epistemic value itself so in
7.4
they're saying we're going to go ahead
and call
just the epistemic value
decomposition term
I
equation 7.8
so here is just a separation of our as
it was written in the prior equation
that is going to be Rewritten
in terms of a KL Divergence
q s and Pi q and s and Pi they're the
same on both sides
here's POS here's q o pi
and it's it's definitely worthwhile I
think for us to write out what these
verbally mean because they have very
I think interesting
um implications for again like what is
the epistemic value
and then here is um with this
semicolon being noted
this is reflecting a pure Information
Gain salience Bayesian surprise
imperative
here's some simulations
showing at like time two it goes to the
to the get the information and then it
proceeds to the left Ali
uh yeah just about your previous remark
about uh why C has the five elements and
D the C is four elements because uh C
actually uh corresponds with the the
elements of a matrices so because a
matrices uh actually describe uh the uh
the hidden the states that the
environment
um uh is dealing with but because D is
corresponds with B Matrix and uh because
B Matrix is a transition Matrix uh
that's why uh we don't need to have a
redundant additional element for that so
D being priors yet Maps unto B Matrix
thanks and right now like you have to
like specify the tensor dimensionality
and add some labels but they're
developing a lot of functions in pi mdp
and people who work with it can
definitely have a lot of feedback
on slightly more intuitive
and scalable ways to specify
dimensionality which is currently one of
the rate limiting steps in pi mdp
application
okay
just getting through seven and then just
so we can look ahead to eight continuous
time so Precision at negative entropy
neg entropy this is the high temperature
and low temperature high temperature
differences are erased
low precision
low temperature absolute zero High
precision
differences are accentuated
that has technical
usage
especially
in certain statistical distributions
isocate paradigm par and Frist in 2017.
isicating is
while our eyes may dwell on what we may
associate with pragmatically valuable
broadly speaking isocating is driven by
Information Gain
so it's a great place to study how
pragmatic semantics
at a higher level
are in a predictive processing type
relationship
with isicating at a lower mechanical
level
with this level almost surely being
driven by Information Gain
learning a novelty here
um one kind of question that was arising
was like why is our dashed line between
only here
but
apart from that
um
priors are being provided
On A and B
so that's sort of like the con again
it's like a little bit like wise B over
here so it's about the topology not not
the geometry in this situation
what's happening is that a prior is
being provided
on a
so that these A and B in principle can
be learnable
how that plays out and how that
influences the pseudocode of the action
perception Loop
Pi mdp is very clear about that
um conjugate priors this is facilitating
like amongst other
um abilities
the the dirichlet conjugate prior for
the categorical distribution so if we
have probability distribution over
categorical outcomes is it hot or cold
then the dear shlay can be used in an
earn counting way
like every time you observe a warm day
or a cold day you just put in a ball of
that color into the urn
and then
it could be 2 and 2 and then the next
ball is very influential it could be a
thousand and a thousand and then the
next ball is not so influential and that
turns out to be what's called a
conjugate prior that enables the
categorical distribution
to stay as a classical probability
distribution
axioms and all of that
while also allowing the conjugate prior
to have this like counting or learning
by Counting
strategy
um inferential approach to learning
this is a difference with many other
areas
they're proposing learning schemes
um
that may or may not be biologically
relevant
whereas a lot of work has gone into
understanding how the perceptual or fast
inference and learning or slower
parameter learning processes are unified
but of distinct time scales and active
inference
um
here in 7 11 equation they are going to
delve more into like learning as active
yes
it's about policy everything's being
conditioned upon policy
there's a lot that one can say about the
integration of action so this maze
learning task
is fundamentally intertwined
with the action selection
the agents updating of their likelihood
is related to their action selection
amidst uncertainty
they're not seen as like two separated
phases
um
here's where they just drop some kind of
threads
and further literature maybe further
versions of the textbook are going to
come into more detail hierarchical deep
inference nested modeling
um something that people talk and think
about a lot
but here we see the figure 4.3 or figure
7.3
the rake and the policy selection
fractal it's a rake of rakes
and
structure learning and Bayesian model
reduction
just some model comparison and Analysis
techniques that support Bayesian
statistics
um
another example
involving a hierarchical inference model
is described
and that has been used in the context of
reading and other visual inference tasks
that's chapter seven let's quickly look
to chapter eight
chapter seven was discrete time
generative models chapter 8 is going to
be continuous time generative models
the main setting in which discrete time
models have been studied is
Central or cognitive decision making
categorical decision making
in contrast the major setting in which
continuous time active inference models
to this time have been used in is in
continuous movement or motor control
tasks so like in live stream 46 active
models do not contradict folk psychology
with Alex Kiefer Ryan Smith and Maxwell
ramstead they talk about like motor AI
Mai and decision active inference Dai
um
here
there's going to be a um
Proto Bayesian physics like
representation that's going to enable us
to do continuous things
specifically the separation of a data
observation
sequence
in terms
of an underlying
um
function and a fluctuation stochastic
term
and then
um a latent States
derivative with a little Dot
change in latent States as a function of
the current status of the Hidden State
and slowly varying causes which are
going to be playing the role of policies
in continuous time formulization and
again partitioning out of our stochastic
fluctuations so actually this part is
allowed is this part is guaranteed to
have zero mean and that's what
facilitates like Bayesian mechanics a
lot of other statistics
um
again just like quickly looking through
it this is y g x and F relationships
continue to be built up
to again talk and this is very SPM like
here's our actual sensor readers
readings from the EEG fmri Meg
their function of neural activity
neural activity is a hidden latent state
it is a function of current neural
activity and attention for example
um
that physics analogy in the continuous
State space
can be extended
into Newtonian Dynamics and as Dalton
and Bayesian mechanics have
laid out in the last year or two it goes
way way further than this
but this is a spring so this is hooke's
law as an as a mere active inference
entity
this is like a boring active entity that
just dampens
but it's just to show that we can
understand the generalized coordinates
of motion
which is to say polish position velocity
acceleration
snap crackle pop
Etc et cetera et cetera generalized
coordinates of motion within this
continuous time
framework
dynamical systems
often which are conditioned to be smooth
and differentiable
are amenable to continuous time
formalizations
in the discrete time we'd say well we
have you know one two and three and then
we're going to be moving to one of the
locations in the grid world
and we have a transition Matrix over
grid world
in the continuous time setting here this
is the spinal cord of the butterfly
here's the sensory data coming in why
and then a descending hidden State
inference
and uh error deviation that's being
resolved through policy selection in the
continuous space
so this is hearkening back to chapter 5
and the spinal cord reflex
how continuous time generative models
can can be applied to continuous spinal
motor reflexes as opposed to the usually
more centrally Associated discrete
categorical decision-making Dai
there's a sidebar on Precision attention
and attenuation
there's the discussion of lock Volterra
which is also called Predator prey or
winner list Dynamics like
you can't win in this ecology there's
also there are ecologies that collapse
of course but activity Dynamics amongst
brain regions
have been modeled for decades as these
winnerless competitions also called
neural Darwinism
and that's relating to friston's
lineage with Edelman
more examples of how these kinds of
winnerless competitions
can be used in the context of continuous
time generative models to generate
smooth action sequences like this sort
of gibberish cursive writing
learning is approached in a continuous
model
everything in chapter 8 is kind of being
contrasted or juxtaposed with what we
saw at chapter 7 in the discrete time
they introduced the Lorenz attractor
which is unpacked in significantly more
detail in live stream 32 on Markov
blankets and stochastic chaos
it is basically this example with the
Lorenz attractor
which is showing that generalized
synchrony which isn't lockstep but
rather Mutual information amongst couple
dynamical systems
can happen even when those coupled
dynamical systems are Lorenz attractors
they don't have to be like both like
simple linear systems
um so that's like good to know and
they've used that to simulate Bird song
where before learning they're kind of
like on and off a synchronization
manifold and then after learning they've
sharpened
their their um
joint distribution
again this begs further questions how do
they know the semantics of a song and
how do they learn the song but this is
just an example
at this level of complexity
um 8.5 Hybrid models here we have the
rake within a rake
but notice that the outer rake there
should be a line connecting this G to Pi
the outer rake is Dai here we see hidden
States Through Time T minus one now
future Tale of Two densities
observations Through Time classic Dai
chapter 7 up top
but the nested model
has the same structure figure 4.3 but
here we see the position
velocity acceleration generalized
coordinates pattern occurring
so this is called a hybrid model because
the discrete time model is nesting a
continuous time model
so this has been used to model things
like where do I want to look from a
categorical perspective and then here's
the oculomotor cicades at a continuous
model that's nested within that
more equations
isucade model
summary and key advances in continuous
time models
end of the chapter all right thank you
we'll take a break and then begin with
the next cohort in just two minutes